unh.edu 2014-06-19

# University System of New Hampshire Privacy Policy

**Our Commitment To Privacy**

Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy we provide this policy explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this policy easy to find, we make it available on our homepage and at every point where personally identifiable information may be requested.

**The Information We Collect:**

This policy applies to all information collected or submitted on the University System of New Hampshire website. On some pages, you can request information, make requests, and register to receive materials. The types of personal information collected at these pages are:

> Name   
>  Address   
>  Email address   
>  Phone number   
>  (etc.) 

On some pages, you can submit information about other people. For example, if you recommend a colleague for services, you will need to submit the recipient's address. In this circumstance, the types of personal information collected are:

> Name   
>  Address   
>  Phone Number   
>  (etc.) 

**The Way We Use Information:**

We use the information you provide about yourself when placing a request only to complete that request to the best of our ability. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to complete that request.

We use return email addresses to answer the email we receive. Such addresses are not used for any other purpose and are not shared with outside parties. 

We use non-identifying and aggregate information to better design our website and to share with advertisers. For example, we may tell an advertiser that X number of individuals visited a certain area on our website, or that Y number of men and Z number of women filled out our registration form, but we would not disclose anything that could be used to identify those individuals.

Finally, we never use or share the personally identifiable information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described above without also providing you an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated uses.

**Our Commitment To Data Security**

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

**Our Commitment To Children's Privacy:**

We are committed to protecting the privacy of the very young. While our websites are generally not directed at or intended to attract visitors under age 13, our institutions do run certain programs for children for which online registration or participation is available. For those activities, the following additional **Children's Privacy Policy** supplements this USNH Privacy Policy.

> **Children's Privacy**
> 
> We recognize the need to provide additional privacy protections when information is collected from or about children under the age of 13. The following guidelines apply to activities (including but not limited to on-campus camps or lessons for children and online activities designed for children), in addition to our general Privacy Policy. These rules follow the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA).
> 
> **Information We May Collect**
> 
> We may collect the following information about a child who will participate in a USNH-administered youth activity:
>
>> Name  
>  E-mail address  
>  Street address  
>  Date of birth (to ensure enrollment in age-appropriate activities) 
> 
> Depending upon the activities in which your child chooses to participate, your child may be asked or choose to provide additional information. We do not require a person to disclose more information than is reasonably necessary to participate in an activity.
> 
> **How We Use the Information**
> 
> We use the information about your child to register your child for a USNH event and to insure appropriate content and safety for participants. USNH and its institutions will not disclose a child's information to any third party without parental authorization, except as may otherwise be required by law.
> 
> **Parent/Guardian Consent**
> 
> We will not collect or store online information from or about a child under age 13 until we have received a parent's or guardian's verified consent.
> 
> Parents or Guardians may review their child'sqqpersonal information in our online databases; correct factual inaccuracies in the information collected about their child; refuse to permit us to collect further personal information from their child; and ask that information be deleted from our online records. Appropriate contact information for parents will be provided on every webpage promoting or permitting activities by children under age 13.
> 
> **COPPA Notice Template**
> 
> [A Children's Online Privacy and Protection Act ("COPPA") notice template](http://usnh.edu/olpm/USY/VI.Prop/USNH_COPPA_Notice_Template.pdf) is provided for use by the institutions of USNH.

**How You Can Access Or Correct Your Information**

You can access all your personally identifiable information that we collect online and maintain by contacting us directly via phone or e-mail. We use this procedure to better safeguard your information.

You can correct factual errors in your personally identifiable information by sending us a request that credibly shows error.

To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections.

**How To Contact Us**

Should you have other questions or concerns about these privacy policies, please [contact us](http://www.usnh.edu/hr/SystemOfficeHR/systemcontacts.html).

* * *

**1**Online Policy Manual (OLPM) reference: USY VI.F.7
